when creating word documents there will
be situations where you need to display
certain information in a table format
word has tools within itself to allow
you to do this
and i'm going to demonstrate them here
the first way to insert a table is to go
to the insert tab and click on that
and then select the table icon and
just below there as i start to move my
mouse down
the rows and then across it
automatically starts to insert
that amount of columns and rows within
to the letter
when i'm happy with the number of
columns and rules i want just click
and it will automatically insert them
the problem there is is that i still
need to
populate the table an alternative to
this is importing information from
another document
and then converting that into a table
the first thing i'm going to do is undo
that
so that is now clear i will then open
the spreadsheet that i downloaded from
the vision alone website which contains
the information that i'm going to use
so what i need to do is i need to copy
this information so i'll click
and hold and drag it down and across and
then select the copy icon
now that i have copied that information
i can then go back to the letter
and select paste so as you can see it
has now pasted the information
into the letter i now have several
options
so if i click on the little drop down on
the paste options button
it gives me the option to keep the
source formatting
use the destination styles link and keep
link and use destination styles insert
as a picture or keep the text on me
for this example i'm going to keep the
text only
so as you can see it has now inserted
that text into the letter
but it isn't presented in a very nice
format
what i need to do now is i need to
convert that text
into a table to do that i need to
highlight
all of the text and then go back to the
insert tab
so i click on insert and go to table and
then select convert text to table
so word is actually identifying where
the spacing is occurring
within each of those pieces of text and
it's automatically identified that it
needs to have three columns and eight
rows
it is separated by the tabs
so i click ok that will insert the text
into a table
once i have the information into the
table i then want to apply some
formatting
if i double click on the icon at the top
left of the table it will open up the
table design tab
from there i can apply table styles
shading border styles variety of
different things
in this example all i'm going to do is
just to add some shading
to the top border once that's done
and i'm happy that it looks okay i can
then save the document